<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" version="2.0" xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"><channel><title>ImportError (wsgi)</title><link>http://k4ml.github.io</link><description></description><atom:link href="http://k4ml.github.io/categories/wsgi.xml" type="application/rss+xml" rel="self"></atom:link><language>en</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2015 12:18:43 GMT</lastBuildDate><generator>Nikola &lt;http://getnikola.com/&gt;</generator><docs>http://blogs.law.harvard.edu/tech/rss</docs><item><title>Django: Where does the application start ?</title><link>http://k4ml.github.io/posts/django-where-does-the-application-start.html</link><description>&lt;div&gt;&lt;p&gt;The key to understand any kind of application is to know where does it start. Until
then you'll keep banging your head, shooting in the dark and lastly, at the mercy
of Google when trying to debug or solve any issues you have.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Majority of web developers don't really know, or even care where actually their application
start. This particularly true for those developing in PHP which abstract most of the web parts
and it appear to developer they just writing a regular command line or desktop application.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For Django developer, you can probably ignore this throughout your dev carrier but knowing it
will help you a lot in.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Django application can start (at least) from 2 possible entry point. The first entry point is
through the development server and the second entry point is when you deploy it to production
web server, either &lt;code&gt;mod_wsgi&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;gunicorn&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Paste&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Rocket&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Waitress&lt;/code&gt;, &lt;code&gt;Circus&lt;/code&gt; or dozen more
WSGI server you can find on PyPI. I can still remember the day when there's none pure Python
WSGI server exists (except CherryPy) and how I'd really envy Rails's community for having Mongrel.
That day has long gone.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class="more"&gt;&lt;a href="http://k4ml.github.io/posts/django-where-does-the-application-start.html"&gt;Read more…&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</description><category>django</category><category>wsgi</category><category>learn</category><guid>http://k4ml.github.io/posts/django-where-does-the-application-start.html</guid><pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2014 08:00:14 GMT</pubDate></item></channel></rss>